Guide to the Geoffrey Weiss punk collection, circa 1970-2000.
Weiss, Geoffrey punk collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Geoffrey Weiss punk collection, circa 1970-2000.
8054
Geoffrey, Weiss
2.2 cubic feet.
Printed material and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Punk and underground music related magazines and fanzines. Also files on bands and punk venues that include flyers, posters, and other ephemera. The remainder of the collection, which includes 500 LP, 45, and CD recordings, along with approximately 100 related books have been cataloged individually.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Punk and underground music related magazines and fanzines. Also files on bands and punk venues that include flyers, posters, and other ephemera. The remainder of the collection, which includes 500 LP, 45, and CD recordings, along with approximately 100 related books have been cataloged individually.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Weiss, Geoffrey
Subjects:
Punk rock music.; Punk culture.; Popular music -- 1971-1980.; Punk rock music -- 1971-1980.; Rock music -- 1971-1980.; Punk culture; Punk rock music
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Magazines and Fanzines
Series II. Band and Record Label Files
Series IV. Flyers
Series V. Sound and Video Recordings
Series VI. Ephemera
CONTAINER LIST
- Magazines and Fanzines, 1973-1996
  - A-G, 1977-1997
    - Action Teen, 1988; Smith, Don; Smith, Erin (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Bethesda, Maryland
      Fugazi
      Unrest
      Beat Happening
    - Alternative Rhythms, 1986-01; Rosenthal, Sam (Box 18, Folder 2)
      No. 23
      Cooper City, Florida
      New Order
      Cloth, The
      Minutemen, The
      Lone Justice
      Dead Kennedys
    - Apokalypse Now, Winter 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Zurich, Switzerland
    - Away from the Pulsebeat, 1987; Art (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Hoboken, New Jersey
      Celibate Rifles, The
      Killdozer
    - B Side, 1984-1986; Lonergan, Simon (Box 18, Folder 5)
      No. 17/18 and "Greatest Hits!" issue
      Harvey, Mick
      New South Wales, Australia
      Harem Scarem
      Birthday Party, The
      Celibate Rifles
      White Cross
    - Back Door Man, Winter 1987; Faye, D.D.; Gardner, Thom; Meyers, Bob; Patterson, Fred; Turner, Gregg; Waller, Don (Box 18, Folder 6)
      No. 14
      Smith, Patti
      Costello, Elvis
      Parker, Graham
      Torrance, California
      Dead Boys, The
      Sex Pistols
    - Ballroom Blitz, 1977-03-1977-11; Heddle, Jim; McDowell, Mike (Box 18, Folder 7)
      No. 19, 23
      Shannon, Tom
      Nelson, Rick
      Dearborn Heights, Michigan
      Sonic's Rendezvous Band
      Cheap Trick
    - Big Meat Eater, 1985; Gonzalez, David; Hinsch, David (Box 18, Folder 8)
      No. 2
      Cincinnati, Ohio
    - Bikini Girl, 1978-06-1979-02; Baumgardner, Lisa; Spaeth, Brian (Box 18, Folder 9)
      No. 3 and an unnumbered issue
      New York, New York
    - Blitz, 1982-03-1982-08; McDowell, Mike (Box 18, Folder 10)
      No. 42-43
      Erickson, Roky
      Los Angeles, California
    - Blurt, 1986; Ehlers, Michael (Box 18, Folder 11)
      Spicer, Minnesota
      Urge Overkill
    - Boyfriends, 1977; McAree, Macs; Smyth, Michael; D.U.O. Communications Inc. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Vol. 1, No. 1
      United Kingdom
    - Bucketfull of Brains, 1980-1989; Cross, Nigel W. (Box 18, Folder 12)
      No. 9-10, 15 (2 copies), 16-18, 28
      Hitchcock, Robyn
      Case, Peter
      London, United Kingdom
      Rain Parade
      Church, The
      Dream Syndicate, The
      Flamin' Groovies
      Big Dipper
    - Sad Eyes Kill, 1984; SR-20749; Rain Parade; Enigma Records (Box 18, Folder 12)
      BOB 4; 7" flexi accompanying Bucketfull of Brains no. 10
    - Bullet, 1982-01; Benton, Bruce; Cade, Dave (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Lawrence, Kansas
      Panther Burns
    - Chickfactor, Fall-Winter 1996-1997; O'Hara, Gail (Box 18, Folder 14)
      No. 10
      Cosloy, Gerard
      Schulman, Michael
      Sleater-Kinney
      Yips, The
      Cat Power
      Magnetic Fields, The
    - Citizen Arrest, 1985; Steele, Andy (Box 18, Folder 15)
      No. 4
      Southboro, Massachusetts
      Suicidal Tendencies
      Hüsker Dü
      Positive Outlook
    - Cle, 1989; Ellis, James (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Cleveland, Ohio
      Electric Eels
    - Conflict, 1984-1986; Cosloy, Gerard (Box 18, Folder 16)
      No. 35-37, 39-40
      Burns, Robert
      Wayland, Massachusetts
      Turbines
      Saccharine Trust
      Live Skull
      Soul Asylum
    - Creem, 1973-06 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      Partial issue
    - Cryptic Times, 1990; Madam X.; Dr. Weasel (Box 18, Folder 18)
      No. 1
      Ontario, Canada
      Beatpack, The
      Smugglers, The
      Fuzztones, The
    - D.I.Y., Fall 1990; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Manhattan Beach, California
    - D.I.Y., 1981-01-1981-02; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Vol. 1, No. 2
      Myrick, Gary
      Robinson, Tom
    - D.I.Y., 1981-03; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Vol. 1, No. 3
      Plasmatics, The
    - D.I.Y., 1981-04; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Vol. 1, No. 4
      U2
    - D.I.Y., 1981-05; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 6)
      No. 5
      Boomtown Rats, The
    - D.I.Y., 1981-06; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 7)
      No. 6
      X
      Cramps, The
      Split Enz
    - D.I.Y., 1981-08; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 8)
      No. 8
      Psychedelic Furs
    - D.I.Y., 1982-03; Taylor, Jonathan; Lamson, Chris (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Hollywood, California
      Police, The
    - D.N.A., 1986-10 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      No. 53; Australian Punk and Post-Punk Record and Tape Discography
      Adelaide, Australia
    - Destroy All Monsters, 1978; Loren, Cary (Box 18, Folder 20)
      No. 2-4
      Southfield, Michigan
    - Disaster, 1987-02; Callahan, Bill (Box 18, Folder 21)
      No. 3
      Pasadena, Maryland
      Phantom Tollbooth
    - Down Town, 1978; Kemp, Nick (Box 18, Folder 22)
      Thunders, Johnny
      Blondie
      Tanz Der Youth
      Generation X
    - Fiz, 1994-04-1994-05; McConnell, Wendy; Rundell, Cathy (Box 18, Folder 23)
      No. 11
      Ramones
      Devo
      Beck
      Archers of Loaf
      Unsane
      Zipgun
      Snatch
    - Forced Exposure, 1986; Johnson, Jimmy (Box 18, Folder 24)
      No. 9
      Cave, Nick
      Lunch, Lydia
      Newtonville, Massachusetts
      Mission of Burma
      Big Black
      Half Japanese
      Couch Flambeau
      Flaming Lips
    - Foreign Object, The, 1986-11; Danno, Steven (Box 18, Folder 25)
      Sydney, Australia
      Fun Things
    - Los Angeles Phonograph Record Magazine, The, 1978-01; Cerf, Martin (Box 19, Folder 1)
      John, Elton
      Martin, Steve
      DeShannon, Jackie
    - MasterBag, Winter 1986; Cranna, Ian (Box 19, Folder 2)
      No. 13 (2 copies), 14
      Dixon, Steve
      Passage, The
      Pale Fountains, The
    - Blue, 1982-07-08-1982-07-21; SR-20750; Haig, Paul; Masterbag (Box 19, Folder 2)
      BAG 003; 7" flexi accompanying Masterbag no. 13
    - Gut Level, 1982; SR-20852; Cabaret Voltaire; Masterbag; Rough Trade Records (Box 19, Folder 2)
      BAG 004; 7" flexi accompanying Masterbag no. 14
    - Matter, 1984-07-1984-08; Phillip, Elizabeth (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Evanston, Illinois
      Echo and the Bunnymen
      Meat Puppets, The
    - Merrittville Chronicle, The, 1988-01; Linda (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Monomania, 1977-07; Brad (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Nonantum, Massachusetts
  - N-Z, 1974-1995
    - New Society, 1977-01-20; Barker, Paul (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Vol. 39, No. 746
      Sex Pistols, The
      Clash, The
    - Non LP, 1981-10; Amber, Margery; Ufner, Daniel (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Lawrence, New York
      Au Pairs
      Pigbag Payback
    - Objekt, 1984; Frith, Julie; Ladd, Brian (Box 19, Folder 8)
      No. 18
      Eureka, California
    - Offense, The, 1981-08-27; TKA (Box 19, Folder 9)
      Allen, Dave
      Columbus, Ohio
      Gang of Four
    - On the Street, 1986-04-16 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      No. 281
      Waits, Tom
      Chilton, Alex
      Cuckoos, The
      Crystal Set
    - Pazzo, 1982; Sloane, R.K.; Corbin, Teri (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Pro Fun, 1981-06; Beal, Suzanne (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Radio Free Hollywood, 1977-06 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Runaways, The
    - Record Rag, The, 1973-04; Knab, Chris; Aquarius Records, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      San Francisco, California
    - Rollerderby, 1993; Dall, Cindy (Box 19, Folder 14)
      Combustible Edison
    - Search and Destroy, 1978; Vale (Box 23, Folder 11)
      No. 7
      DNA
      Subway Sect
      Cabaret Voltaire
    - Sense of Purpose, 1984; Sprogue, Dave (Box 19, Folder 15)
      Richman, Jonathan
      Salem 66
    - Shake and Pop, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      No. 1, 6
    - Shape of Things, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      Undertones, The
      Nervous Kind, The
    - Sniffin' Glue, 1977; Perry, Mark; Missing cover page (Box 19, Folder 18)
      No. 8, 12
      Jam, The
      Buzzcocks, The
      Sham 69
    - Sporadic Droolings, 1986; Burokas, Dave (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Allin, G.G.
      Kearny, New Jersey
      Shanghai Dog
      Hard-Ons
      Nils, The
      Agent Orange
    - Suburban Relapse, 1983-09; Soltz, Barry (Box 19, Folder 20)
      Vee, Tesco
      North Miami, Florida
      Roach Motel
      Minor Threat
    - Take It!, 1981-01; Koenig, Michael (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Boston, Massachusetts
      Psychedelic Furs, The
      Slits, The
    - Take It!, 1981; Koenig, Michael; Barone, Salvatore (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Alexander, Willie
    - Talk Talk, 1981; Rich, Bill (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Vol. 3, No. 2
      Clarke, Bunny
      Blue Riddim Band, The
    - This is Warr, 1987; Warr, Barb (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Trans-Oceanic Trouser Press, 1974-05-1977-01; Robbins, Ira; Rose, Karen (Box 19, Folder 23)
      No.2-4, 6, 11, 17
      Frampton, Peter
      Beck, Jeff
      Bowie, David
      Fripp, Robert
      Eno, Brian
      Trower, Robert
      Harvey, Alex
      Pink Floyd
      Genesis
      Mott the Hoople
      Yardbirds, The
      Beatles, The
      King Crimson
      Who, The
      Electric Light Orchestra
    - Truly Needy, 1983; Rice, Barbara A. (Box 19, Folder 24)
      Vol. 2, No. 2
      Rockville, Maryland
      Marginal Man
      Fall, The
      T.S.O.L.
      Crass
    - Twist and Shake, 1995-10; Paterson, Beverly (Box 19, Folder 25)
      Vol. 3
      San Mateo, California
      Critics, The
      Dee Jay and the Runaways
    - Waxpaper, 1978-10; Sculatti, Gene; Robinson, Joe (Box 22, Folder 2)
      No. 32
      Martin, Dean
      Burbank, California
      Captain Beefheart
    - Wet, 1978-09-1978-10; Koren, Leonard (Box 19, Folder 26)
      Verlaine, Tom
      Venice, California
      Television
    - Your Flesh, 1988-1990; Davis, Peter (Box 20, Folder 1)
      No. 14, 16-19
      Wray, Link
      Minneapolis, Minnesota
      Death of Samantha
      Babes in Toyland
      L7
      Steel Pole Bath Tub
      Prong
      Helmet
    - Your Flesh, 1992-1993; Davis, Peter (Box 20, Folder 2)
      No. 26, 29
      Carlos, Wendy
      Miller, Frank
      Peel, John
- Band and Record Label Files, 1973-1998
  Includes flyers, clippings, press packs, photographs, and other promotional materials.
  Arranged alphabetically by band/label name
  - Bands, 1973-1998
    - A-J (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Agent Orange, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Includes 3 Agent Orange buttons - MU-1884-1886.
    - Black Flag poster, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Concert poster with Adolescents, D.O.A., and Minutemen at the Santa Monica Civic
    - Circle Jerks, 1980-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Clash, The, 1978-1982 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Dead Boys, The, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Dickies, The, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Fall, The, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Flamin' Groovies, The, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Flipper, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      Contains production cost estimates and artwork for the "Flipper Twist" single.
    - Hell, Richard, Undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Hüsker Dü, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - K-S (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Karate Party, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Manual Scan, 1990; MU-1887 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Includes Manual Scan button (MU-1887).
    - Minutemen, Undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Mumps, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Peel, David, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Ramones, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Red Rockers, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Screamers, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Spliffs, The, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Spooner, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - T-Z (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Tubes, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - U.S. Customs, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Vertebrats poster, Undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Von LMO, 1976-1993 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Weirdos, The, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Record Labels, 1978-1993
    - 4AD, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Big Time Records, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Ork Records, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      Hello, Richard
    - Posh Boy, 1978-03-01 (Box 21, Folder 23)
      Weirdos, The
      Bags, The
      Dils, The
      F-Word!
      Skulls, The
    - Radar, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 24)
      999
    - Reachout, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 25)
      Bad Brains
      Fleshtones, The
    - Slash, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 26)
      Includes advertising rates for Slash magazine and promotional planning for X's "Los Angeles" LP.
      Germs
    - Sub Pop, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Related Materials, 1978-1990
    - Joseph Fox Communications, Inc., 1987-1990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Includes documents and promotional materials for Bug Radio, Music View, New Route, and Rap Down!
      - Soho Natural Sessions, Shows: 3 and 4, 1990; CD-3513; Joseph Fox Communications, Inc.; Soho Natural Soda (Box 20, Folder 3)
        Four copies
        Camper Van Beethoven
      - Music View: Dailies and Promo, 1990; SR-20853; Joseph Fox Communications, Inc.; 7" vinyl record (Box 20, Folder 3)
        1P-7993
    - Miscellaneous Flyers, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Includes advertisements for fanzines and record stores and a "Vote for Nobody" political flyer.
    - Radio Promotions, 1978-1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Flyers, 1976-1987
  - Anti-Club, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Barn, The, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - CBGB, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Club 88, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cuckoos Nest, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Dancing Waters, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Hollywood Palladium, 1972-1982 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Mabuhay Gardens, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Madame Wong's West, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Max's Kansas City, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Olympic Auditorium, 1979-1983 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Other Locations (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Perkins Palace, 1984-1986 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Rave Up!, The, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Roxy, The, 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Unknown Location, 1977-1991 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Vex, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Whiskey, The, 1977-1980 (Box 20, Folder 21)
- Sound and Video Recordings, 1980-2008
  - Live, Undated; TR-16000; Screamers (Box 22)
  - Live at QB, 2008; TR-16001; Sex Vid (Box 22)
    Olympia, Washington
  - Pleasure Heads Must Burn, 1983; VR-10268; Birthday Party, The; Ikon F.C.L. (Box 22)
  - Recording Heathen Earth, Live at Oundle School, 1980; V-10269; Throbbing Gristle; Industrial Records (Box 22)
    Nottingham, United Kingdom
- Ephemera, 1986-1996
  - Ministry "Filthpig" counterstand, 1996; MU-1868 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Mudhoney "Generation Spokesmodel" mirror, 1995; MU-1888 (Box 22)
  - Record store bags, Undated; MU-1866 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Surf Beat '80 backstage pass, 1980; MU-1867 (Box 20, Folder 6)